quarters, Anakin whistled softly to himself, carefully considering what he had learned from Denis. * ** "...And 
if it requires a war to bring the Republic back to its former glory, then perhaps we should be grateful for war." 
Pa!patine ignored the shock around him in the Senate, raising his resonant voice to drown out dissent. "We have 
spent the last century bickering and feuding amongst ourselves. Before the Nechti came to our borders, each 
system fought again?t its neighbor, in armed combat or with economic strangulation. The galaxy wasted many 
lives and credits in these struggles for petty advantage. "nut since the arrival of the Nechti, we have ceased 
our internal quarrels. If we can retain this solidarity after the Nechti are defeated, our combined power will
be greater than ever before." A gaunt woman -near the front said bitterly, "You are quite blithe about the Nechti. 
You would be less so if you had seen the border systems: Avisa stripped to magma; Martelle reft of its atmosphere-- 
my diplomatic suite and I are all that remain of the people of Erenat." Senator Palpatine lowered his eyes. Knife-edged
crescents of gold gleamed from beneath his lids. "I do not wish us to forget the many innocents who have lost their 
homes, their families, or their lives to the Nechti. an think of all the similar losses our internal battles
have claimed. If we can eliminate such sad waste from our Republic by remaining united, then the Nechtian victims 
will not have died in vain. "But let us forget the future for now. We must deal with the present. It is true that
relati?ely few systems have met with the enemy to date, but is there any doubt we must unite now to drive them out?" 
Castra Gatou_ yawned flamboyantly. She was a tawny-haired young woman with pale green eyes; seated in Bail Organa's 
empty chair, she was in the first tier of seats, in excellent view of the council. Almost as an afterthought,
she lifted one languid hand to conceal her mouth. "Why?" she asked. The Erenatese senator lunged to her feet. 
"Why? You've seen the comm holos sent by the Nechti, and you ask why?" "Why not?" Pa!patine turned a speculative 
eye on the young princess, while waving the Erenatese back to her seat. "Your Highness of Alderaan, do your people 
have so little compassion on those less fortunate than themselves?' Castra smiled, showing all her teeth.
"Less fortunate? The border systems brought this war upon themselves. Avisa and Martelle were the planets 
that first met with the Nechti; they made secret trade agreements with them for their technology. They willfully 
violated the laws of the Senate and the Republic by keeping knowledge of the Nechti civilization a secret. And 
you of Erenat--" she gestured at the livid ambassador-- "in fact, your very family signed the Nechti pact with
full intention to violate it. "And once you did... well, small wonder that the Nechti sought revenge on you.
What concern are your border squabbles to the rest of the Republic?" "The Nechti have advanced far past the border 
by now," Palpatine began, but Castra flicked her nails at him. "Past the borders of your own summer planet, you 
mean. Leaving my own opinions aside, you can hardly expect my people to support armed intervention in your internal 
affairs. If you can't maintain civil relations with your neighbors, why should we enforce them for you?" "Civil

