idea of all its parts in his mind, that he can do it when he pleases. If any one who makes his complex idea of justice  
to be, such a treatment of the person or goods of another as is according to law, hath not a clear and distinct idea 
what law is, which makes a part of his complex idea of justice, it is plain his idea of justice itself will be confused 
and imperfect. This exactness will, perhaps, be judged very troublesome; and therefore most men will think
they may be excused from settling the complex ideas of mixed modes so precisely in their minds. But yet I must 
say, till this be done, it must not be wondered, that they have a great deal of obscurity and confusion in their 
own minds, and a great deal of wrangling in their discourse with others. 10. And distinct and conformable ideas
in words that stand for substances. In the names of substances, for a right Use of them, something more is required 
than barely determined ideas. In these the names must also be conformable to things as they exist; but of this
I shall have occasion to speak more at large by and by. This exactness is absolutely necessary in inquiries after 
philosophical knowledge, and in controversies about truth. And though it would be well, too, if it extended 
itself to common conversation and the ordinary affairs of life; yet I think that is scarce to be expected. vulgar 
notions suit vulgar discourses: and both, though confused enough, yet serve pretty well the market and the 
wake. Merchants and lovers, cooks and tailors, have words wherewithal to dispatch their ordinary affairs:
and so, I think, might philosophers and disputants too, if they had a mind to understand, and to be clearly understood. 
11. Third remedy: To apply words to such ideas as common use has annexed them to. Thirdly, it is not enough that
nne-rt have ideas, determined ideas, for which they make these signs stand; but they must also take care to apply 
their words as near as may be to such ideas as common use has annexed them to. For words, especially of languages 
already framed, being no man's private possession, but the common measure of commerce and communication,
it is not for any one at pleasure to change the stamp they are current in, nor alter the ideas they are affixed to; 
or at least, when there is a necessity to do so, he is bound to give notice of it. Men's intentions in spea?ing are, 
or at least should be, to be understood; which cannot be without frequent explanations, demands, and other 
the like incommodious interruptions, where men do not follow common use. Propriety of speech is that which
gives our thoughts entrance into other men's minds with the greatest ease and advantage: and therefore deserves 
some part of our care and study, especially in the names of moral words. The proper signification and use of terms 
is best to be learned from those who in their writings and discourses appear to have had the clearest notions,
and applied to them their terms with the exactest choice and fitness. This way of using a man's words, according
to the propriety of the language, though it have not always the good fortune to be understood; yet most commonly 
leaves the blame of it on him who is so unskilful in the language he speaks, as not to understand it when made use 
of as it ought to be. 12. Fourth remedy: To declare the meaning in which we use them. Fourthly, But, because common

