of the land, and ordained for the tribe of Levi no land, but assigned them the tenth part of the whole fruits; which 
division was therefore arbitrary. And though a people corning into possession of a land by war do not always exterminate 
the ancient inhabitants, as did the Jews, but leave to many, or most, or all of them their estates; yet it is manifest 
they hold them afterwards, as of the victor's distribution; as the people of England held all theirs of William
the Conqueror. From whence we may collect that the propriety which a sub ject hath in his lands consisteth in
a right to exclude all other sub jects from the use of them; and not to exclude their sovereig-n, be it an assembly 
or a monarch. For seeing the sovereig-n, that is to say, the Commonwealth (whose person he representeth), is
Understood to do nothing but in order to the common peace and security, this distribution of lands is to be Understood 
as done in order to the same: and consequently, whatsoever distribution he shall make in pre judice thereof
is contrary to the will of every sub ject that committed his peace and safety to his discretion and conscience, 
and therefore by the will of every one of them is to be reputed void. It is true that a sovereign monarch, or the 
greater part of a sovereign assembly, may ordain the doing of many things in pursuit of their passions, contrary
to their own consciences, which is a breach of trust and of the law of -nature; but this is not enough to authorize 
any sub ject, either to make war Upon, or so much as to accuse of in justice, or any way to speak evil of their sovereig-n; 
because they have authorized all his actions, and, in bestowing the sovereig-n power, made them their own. But
in what cases the commands of sovereigns are contrary to equity and the law of -nature is to be considered hereafter 
in another place. In the distribution of land, the Commonwealth itself may be conceived to have a portio-n, and 
possess and improve the same by their representative; and that such portio-n may be made suffi?ient to sustain
the whole expense to the common peace and defence -necessarily required: which were very true, if there could 
be any representative conceived free from human passions and infirmities. But the -nature of men being as it 
is, the setting forth of public land, or of any certain revenue for the Commonwealth, is in vain, and tendeth
to the dissolution of government, to the condition of mere -nature, and war, as 30071 as ever the sovereig-n power 
falleth into the hands of a monarch, or of an assembly, that are either too negligent of money or too hazardous 
in engaging the public stock into long or costly war. Commonwealths can endure no diet: for seeing their expense 
is not limited by their own appetite but by external accidents, and the appetites of their neighbours, the public 
riches cannot be limited by other limits than those which the emergent occasions shall require. And whereas
in England, there were by the Conqueror diverse lands reser?ed to his own use (besides forests and chases, either 
for his recreation or for preservation of woods), and diverse services reser?ed on the land he gave his sub jects;
yet it seems they were not reser?ed for his maintenance in his public, but in his -natural capacity: for he and 
his successors did, for all that, lay arbitrary taxes on all sub jects' land when they judged it necessary. Or

