his stead. In his days the land was [Wet ten years. 14:2 And Asa did that which was good and right in the eyes of
the LORD his God: 14:3 For he took away the altars of the strange gods, and the high places, and brake down the images, 
and cut down the groves: 14:4 And commanded Judah to seek the LORD God of their fathers, and to do the law and the 
commandment. 14:5 Also he took away out of all the cities of Judah the high places and the images: and the kingdom
was luiet before him. 14:6 And he built fenced cities in Nth: for the land had rest, and he had no war in those 
years; because the LORD had given him rest. 14:7 Therefore he said Unto Judah, Let us build these cities, and 
make about them vv?Ils, and towers, gates, and bars, while the land is yet before Us; because we have sought the 
LORD our God, we have sought him, and he hath given as rest on every side. So they built and prospered. 14:8 And
Asa had an army of men that bare targets and spears, out of Judah three hundred thousand; and out of Ben jamin, 
that bare shi?Ids and drew bows, two hundred and fourscore thousand: all these were mighty men of valour. 14:9
And there came out again2t them Zerah the Ethiopian with an host of a thousand thousand, and three hundred chariots; 
and came Unto Mareshah. 14:10 Then Asa went out again2t him, and they set the battle in array in the valley of Zephathah 
at Mareshah. 14:11 And Asa cried Unto the LORD his God, and said, LORD, it is nothing with thee to help, whether
with many, or with them that have no power: help us, 0 LORD our God; for we rest on thee, and in thy -name we go agai-Ot 
this multitude. 0 LORD, thou art our God; let no man prevail again2t thee. 14:12 So the LORD smote the Ethiopians
before Asa, and before Judah; and the Ethiopians fled. 14:13 And Asa and the people that were with him pursued 
them unto Gerar: and the Ethiopians were overthrow-n, that they could not recover themselves; for they were 
destroyed before the LORD, and before his host; and they carried away very much spoil. 14:14 And they smote all 
the cities round about Gerar; for the fear of the LORD came upon them: and they spoiled all the cities; for there 
was exceeding much spoil in them. 14:15 They smote also the tents of cattle, and carried away sheep and camels
in abundance, and returned to Jerusalem. 15:1 And the Spirit of God came upon Azariah the son of Oded: 15:2 And
he went out to meet Asa, and said unto him, Hear ye me, Asa, and all Judah and Ben jamin; The LORD is with you, while 
ye be with him; and if ye seek him, he will be found of you; but if ye forsake him, he will forsake you. 15:3 Now for
a long season Israel hath been without the true God, and without a teaching priest, and without law. 15:4 Bill
when they in their trouble did turn unto the LORD God of Israel, and sought him, he was found of them. 15:5 And in 
those times there was no peace to him that went out, -nor to him that came i-n, but great vexations were upon all the 
inhabitants of the [Gantries. 15:6 And nation was destroyed of nation, and city of city: for God did vex them
with all adversity. 15:7 Be ye strong therefore, and let not your hands be weak: for your work shall be rewarded.
15:8 And when Asa heard these words, and the prophecy of Oded the prophet, he took cour?ge, and put away the abominable 
idols out of all the land of Judah and Ben jamin, and out of the cities which he had taken from mount Ephraim, and

