and the strangers with them out of Ephraim and Manasseh, and out of Simeon: for they fell to him out of Israel in 
abUndance, when they saw that the LORD his God was with him. 15:10 So they gathered themselves tog?ther at Jerusalem 
in the third month, in the fifteenth year of the reign of Asa. 15:11 And they offered unto the LORD the same time,
of the spoil which they had brought, seven hundred oxen and seven thousand sheep. 15:12 And they entered into 
a covenant to seek the LORD God of their fathers with all their heart and with all their soul; 15:13 That whosoever
would not seek the LORD God of Israel should be put to death, whether small or great, whether man or woman. 15:14 
And they sware unto the LORD with a loud voice, and with shouting, and with trumpets, and with cornets. 1515 
And all Judah re joiced at the oath: for they had sworn with all their heart, and sought him with their whole desire;
and he was found of them: and the LORD gave them rest round about. 15:16 And also concerning Maachah the mother 
of Asa the king, he removed her from being luee-n, because she had made an idol in a grove: and Asa cut down her idol,
and stamped it, and burnt it at the brook Kiclron. 15:17 But the high places were not taken away out of Israel: -nevertheless 
the heart of Asa was perfect all his days. 15:18 And he brought into the house of God the things that his father
had dedicated, and that he himself had dedicated, silver, and gold, and vessels. 15:19 And there was no more
war unto the five and thirtieth year of the reign of Asa. 16:1 In the six and thirtieth year of the reign of Asa Baasha 
king of Israel came up againfl Judah, and built Ramah, to the intent that he might let -none go out or come in to Asa 
king of Judah. 16:2 Then Asa brought out silver and gold out of the treasures of the house of the LORD and of the 
king's house, and sent to eenhadad king of Syria, that dwelt at Damascus, saying, 16:3 There is a league between
me and thee, as there was between my father and thy father: behold, I have sent thee silver and gold; go, break 
thy league with saasha king of Israel, that he may depart from me. 16:4 And Benhadad hear?ened unto king Asa, 
and sent the captains of his armies again2t the cities of Israel; and they smote I jo-n, and Da-n, and Abelmaim, 
and all the store cities of Naphtali. 16:5 And it came to pass, when Baasha heard it, that he left off Wading
of Ramah, and let his work cease. 16:6 Then Asa the king took all Judah; and they carried away the stones of Ramah, 
and the timber thereof, wherewith saasha was bUilding; and he built therewith Geba and Mizpah. 16:7 And at that 
time hanani the seer came to Asa king of Judah, and said unto him, Because thou hast relied on the king of Syria, 
and not relied on the LORD thy God, therefore is the host of the king of Syria escaped out of thine hand. 16:8 Were 
not the Ethiopians and the Lubims a huge host, with very many chariots and horsemen? yet, because thou didst 
rely on the LORD, he delivered them into thine hand. 16:9 For the eyes of the LORD run to and fro throughout the 
whole earth, to shew himself strong in the behalf of them whose heart is perfect toward him. Herein thou hast 
done foolishly: therefore from henceforth thou shalt have wars. 16:10 Then Asa was wroth with the seer, and
put him in a prison house; for he was in a rage with him because of this thing. And Asa oppressed some of the people

