have retained -nearly the same character from an enormously remote geological period, so certain species have 
migrated over vast spaces, and have not become greatly or at all modified. According to these views, it is obvious
that the several species of the same genus, though inhabiting the most distant quarters of the world, must originally 
have proceeded from the same source, as they are descended from the same progenitor. In the case of those species 
which have undergone during the whole geological periods little modification, there is not much difficulty
in believing that they have migrated from, the same region; for during the vast geographical and climatal changes 
which have supervened since ancient times, almost any amount of migration is possible. But in many other cases, 
in which we have reason to believe that the species of a geniis have been produced within comparatively recent 
times, there is great difficulty on this head. It is also obvious that the individuals of the same species, though 
now inhabiting distant and isolated regions, must have proceeded from one spot, where their parents were first 
produced: for, as has been explained, it is incredible that individuals identically the same should have been 
produced from parents specifically distinct. Single Centres of supposed Creation.- We are thus brought to
the question which has been largely discussed by -naturalists, namely, whether species have been created at
one or more points of the earth's surface. Undoubtedly there are many cases of extreme difficulty in Understanding 
how the same species could possibly have migrated from some one point to the several distant and isolated points, 
where now found. Nevertheless the simplicity of the view that each species was first produced within a single
region captivates the mind. He who rejects it, rejects the very causa of ordinary generation with subsequent 
migration, and calls in the agency of a miracle. It is Universally admitted, that in most cases the area inhabited 
by a species is continuous; and that when a plant or animal inhabits two points so distant from each other, or 
with an interval of such a -nature, that the space could not have been easily passed over by migration, the fact 
is given as something remarkable and exceptional. The incapacity of migrating across a wide sea is more clear
in the case of terrestrial mammals than perhaps with any other organic beings; and, accordingly, we find no 
inexplicable instances of the same mammals inhabiting distant points of the world. No geologist feels any 
difficulty in Great Britain possessing the same quadrupeds with the rest of Europe, for they were no doubt once
United. But if the same species can be produced at two separate points, why do we not find a single mammal common 
to Europe and Australia or South America? The conditions of life are nearly the same, so that a multitude of EUropea-n 
animals and plants have become naturalised in America and Australia; and some of the aboriginal plants are
identically the same at these distant points of the northern and southern hemispheres. The answer, as I believe, 
is, that mammals have not been able to migrate, whereas some plants, from their varied means of dispersal, have 
migrated across the wide and broken interspaces. The great and striking influence of barriers of all kinds,

