as the terms of admission are more or less difficult; and according as the directors of the company have more
or less autkarity, or have it more or less in their power to manage in such a manner as to confine the greater part 
of the trade to themselves and their particular friends. In the most ancient regulated companies the privileges 
of apprenticeship were the same as in other corporations, and entitled the person who had ser2e4 his time to
a member of the company to become himself a member, either without paying any fine, or upon paying a much smaller 
one than what was exacted of other people. The usual corporation spirit, wherever the law does not restrain
it, prevails in all regulated companies. \Nhe-n they have been allowed to act according to their -natural genius, 
they have always, in order to confine the competition to as small a -number of persons as possible, endeavoured
to sub ject the trade to many bitrde-n some regulations. \Nhe-n the law has restrained them from doing this, they 
have become altog?ther useless and insignificant. The regulated companies for foreign commerce which at
present subsist in Great Britain are the ancient merchant adventurers' company, now commonly called the Hamburg 
Company, the Russia Company, the Eastland Company, the Turkey Company, and the African Company. The terms 
of admission into the Hamburg Company are now said to be luite easy, and the directors either have it not their 
power to sub ject the trade to any bUridensorne restraint or regulations, or, at least, have not of late exercised
that power. It has not always been so- About the middle of the last century, the fine for admission was fifty,
and at one time one hundred pounds, and the conduct of the company was said to be extremely oppressive. In 1643, 
in 1645, and in 1661, the clothiers and free traders of the West of England complained of them to Parliament as
of monopolists who confined the trade and oppressed the manufactures of the cotntry. Though those complains 
produced an Act of Parliament, they had probably intimidated the company so far as to oblige them to reform their 
conduct. Since that time, at least, there has been no complaints again2t them. By the 10th and 11th of William
III, c. 6, the fine for admission into the Russia Company was reduced to five pounds; and by the 25th of Charles 
II, c. 7, that for admission into the Eastland Company to forty shillings, while, at the same time, Swede-n, Denmark, 
and Norway, all the countries on the -north side of the Baltic, were exempted from their exclusive charter. The 
conduct of those companies had probably given occasion to those two Acts of Parliament. Before that time, Sir 
Josiah Child had represented both these and the Hamburg Company as extremely oppressive, and imputed to their 
bad management the low state of the trade which we at that time carried on to the countries comprehended within 
their respective charters. eat though such companies may not, in the present times, be very oppressive, they
are certainly altog?ther useless. To be merely useless, indeed, is perhaps the highest eulogy which can ever
justly be bestowed upon a regulated company; and all the three companies above mentioned seem, in their present 
state, to deserve this eulogy. The fine for admission into the TUrkey Company was formerly twenty-five pounds

