to the wisdom of future statesmen and legislators to determine. Five different events, unforeseen and unthought 
of, have very fortunately concurred to hinder Great Britain from feeling, so sensibly as it was generally expected
she would, the total exclusion which has now taken place for more than a year (from the first of December, 1774) 
from a very important branch of the colony trade, that of the twelve associated provinces of North America. 
First, those colonies, in preparing themselves for their non-importation agreement, drained Great Britain 
completely of all the commodities which were fit for their market; secondly, the extraordinary demand of the 
Spanish Flota has, this year, drained Germany and the North of many commodities, linen in particular, which 
Used to come into competition, even in the British market, with the manufactures of Great Britain; thirdly,
the peace between Russia and Turkey has occasioned an extraordinary demand from the Turkey market, which, 
during the distress of the cou?try, and while a Russian fleet was cruising in the Archipelago, had been very 
poorly supplied; fourthly, the demand of the North of Europe for the manufactures of Great Britain has been 
increasing from year to year for some time past; and fifthly, the late partition and conseluential pacification
of Poland, by opening the market of that great cotfltry, have this year added an extraordinary demand from thence 
to the increasing demand of the North. These events are all, except the fourth, in their nature transitory and 
accidental, and the exclusion from so important a branch of the colony trade, if unfortunately it should continue 
much longer, may still occasion some degree of distress. This distress, however, as it will come on gradually,
will be felt much less severely than if it had come on all at once; and, in the meantime, the industry and capital 
of the cou?try may find a new employment and direction, so as to prevent this distress from ever rising to any 
considerable height. The monopoly of the colony trade, therefore, so far as it has turned towards that trade
a greater proportion of the capital of Great Britain than what would otherwise have gone to it, has in all cases 
turned it, from a foreign trade of consumption with a neighbouring into one with a more distant cou?try; in many 
cases, from a direct foreign trade of consumption into a round-about one; and in some cases, from all foreign 
trade of consumption into a carrying trade. It has in all cases, therefore, turned it from a direction in which
it would have maintained a greater quantity of productive labour into one in which it can maintain a much smaller 
quantity. By suiting, besides, to one particular market only so great a part of the industry and commerce of 
Great Britain, it has rendered the whole state of that industry and commerce more precarious and less secure 
than if their produce had been accommodated to a greater variety of markets. We must carefully distinguish
between the effects of the colony trade and those of the monopoly of that trade. The former are always and necessarily 
beneficial; the latter always and necessarily hurtful. But the former are so beneficial that the colony trade,
though sub ject to a monopoly, and notwithstanding the hurtful effects of that monopoly, is still upon the whole

