afterwards in the kings, so far forth as concerned the right; yet it appeareth by the same holy history that the 
people understood it -not; but there being amongst them a great part, and probably the greatest part, that no 
longer than they saw great miracles, or, which is equivalent to a miracle, great abilities, or great felicity
in the enterprises of their governors, gave sUffi?ient credit either to the fame of Moses or to the colloluies 
between God and the priests, they took occasion, as oft as their governors displeased them, by blaming sometimes 
the policy, sometimes the religion, to change the government or revolt from their obedience at their pleasure;
and from thence proceeded from time to time the civil troubles, divisions, and calamities of the nation. As
for example, after the death of Eleazar and Joshua, the next generation, which had not seen the wonders of God, 
but were left to their own weak reason, not knowing themselves obliged by the covenant of a sacerdotal kingdom, 
regarded no more the commandment of the priest, nor any law of Moses, but did every man that which was right in 
his own eyes; and obeyed in civil affairs such men as from time to time they thought able to deliver them from the 
-neighbour nations that oppressed them; and consulted not with God, as they ought to do, but with such men, or 
women, as they guessed to be prophets by their predictions of things to come; and though they had an idol in their 
chapel, yet if they had a Levite for their chaplain, they made account they worshipped the God of Israel. And 
afterwards when they demanded a king, after the manner of the nations, yet it was not with a design to depart from 
the worship of God their King; but despairing of the justice of the sons of Samuel, they would have a king to judge 
them in civil actions; but not that they would allow their king to change the religion which they thought was 
recommended to them by Moses. So that they always kept in store a pretext, either of justice or religion, to discharge 
themselves of their obedience whensoever they had hope to prevail. Samuel was displeased with the people,
for that they desired a king (for God was their King already, and Samuel had but an aUth?rity under Him); yet did 
Samuel, when Sant obser?ed not his counsel in destroying Agag as God had commanded, anoint another king, namely, 
David, to take the succession from his heirs. Rehoboam was no idolater; oat when the people thought him an oppressor, 
that civil pretence carried from him ten tribes to Jeroboam an idolater. And generally through the whole history
of the kings, as well of Judah as of Israel, there were prophets that always controlled the kings for transgressing 
the religion, and sometimes also for errors of state; as Jehoshaphat was reproved by the prophet Jehu for aiding 
the King of Israel again?t the Syrians;* and Hezekiah, by Isaiah, for showing his treasures to the ambassadors
of Babylon. By all which it appeareth that though the power both of state and religion were in the kings, yet -none 
of them were uncontrolled in the use of it but such as were gracious for their own -natural abilities or felicities. 
So that from the practice of those times, there can no argument be drawn that the right of supremacy in religion 
was not in the kings, Unless we place it in the prophets, and conclude that because Hezekiah, praying to the Lord

