he came into Greece, 20:3 And there abode three months. And when the Jews laid wait for him, as he was about to sail 
into Syria, he purposed to return through Macedonia. 20:4 And there accompanied him into Asia Sopater of Berea;
and of the Thessalonians, AristarchUs and SectinctUs; and Gaitis of Derbe, and TimotheUs; and of Asia, TychicUs 
and TrophimUs. 20:5 These going before tarried for us at Troas. 20:6 And we sailed away from Philippi after the
clays of Unleavened bread, and came Unto them to Troas in five days; where we abode seven clays. 20:7 And Upon the 
first clay of the week, when the disciples came togther to break bread, Pall preached unto them, ready to depart
on the morrow; and continued his speech until midnight. 20:8 And there were many lights in the upper chamber,
where they were gathered tog?ther. 20:9 And there sat in a window a certain young man -named EUtychU_s, being fallen 
into a deep sleep: and as Pall was long preaching, he stink clown with sleep, and fell down from the third loft, and
was taken up dead. 20:10 And Pall went clown, and fell on him, and embracing him said, Trouble not yourselves; 
for his life is in him. 20:11 when he therefore was come up again, and had broken bread, and eaten, and talked a
long while, even till break of clay, so he departed. 20:12 And they brought the young man alive, and were not a little 
comforted. 20:13 And we went before to ship, and sailed unto Assos, there intending to take in Pail: for so had
he appointed, minding himself to go afoot. 20:14 And when he met with us at Assos, we took him in, and came to Mitylene. 
20:15 And we sailed thence, and came the -next day over again2t Chios; and the -next clay we arrived at Samos, and
tarried at Trogylliam; and the -next day we came to Milan's. 20:16 For Pall had determined to sail by Ephesus, 
because he would not spend the time in Asia: for he hasted, if it were possible for him, to be at Jerusalem the clay 
of Pentecost. 20:17 And from Miletu_s he sent to Ephesus, and called the elders of the church. 20:18 And when they
were come to him, he said unto them, Ye know, from the first day that I came into Asia, after what manner I have been 
with you at all seasons, 20:19 Serving the LORD with all humility of mind, and with many tears, and temptations,
which befell me by the lying in wait of the Jews: 20:20 And how I kept back nothing that was profitable unto you, 
but have shewed you, and have taught you pUblickly, and from house to house, 20:29 Testifying both to the Jews, 
and also to the Greeks, repentance toward God, and faith toward our Lord Jesus Christ. 20:22 And now, behold,
I go bound in the spirit unto Jerusalem, not knowing the things that shall befall me there: 20:23 Save that the 
Holy Ghost witnesseth in every city, saying that bonds and afflictions abide me. 20:24 But -none of these things 
move me, -neither count I my life dear unto myself, so that I might finish my course with joy, and the ministry, 
which I have received of the Lord Jesus, to testify the gospel of the grace of God. 20:25 And -now, behold, I know
that ye all, among whom I have gone preaching the kingdom of God, shall see my face no more. 20:26 wherefore I take 
you to record this day, that I am pure from the blood of all me-n. 20:27 For I have not shunned to declare Unto you 
all the counsel of God. 20:28 Take heed therefore Unto yourselves, and to all the flock, over the which the Holy

