principally on external objects, as war, peace, negotiation, and foreign commerce; with which last the power
of taxation will, for the most part, be connected. The powers reser?ed to the several States will extend to all 
the ob jects which, in the ordinary course of affairs, concern the lives, liberties, and properties of the people, 
and the internal order, improvement, and prosperity of the State. The operations of the federal government
will be most extensive and important in times of war and danger; those of the State governments, in times of peace 
and security. As the former periods will probably bear a small proportion to the latter, the State governments
will here en joy another advantage over the federal government. The more ade4uate, indeed, the federal powers 
may be rendered to the national defense, the less frellUent will be those scenes of danger which might favor their 
ascendancy over the governments of the particular States. If the new ConstitUtion be examined with accuracy 
and candor, it will be found that the change which it proposes consists much less in the additio-n of NEW POWERS 
to the Union, than in the invigoration of its ORIGINAL POWERS. The regulation of commerce, it is true, is a new 
power; but that seems to be an additio-n which few oppose, and from which no apprehensions are entertained. The 
powers relating to war and peace, armies and fleets, treaties and finance, with the other more considerable
powers, are all vested in the existing Congress by the articles of Confederation. The proposed change does
not enlarge these powers; it only substitutes a more effectual mode of administering them. The change relating 
to taxation may be regarded as the most important; and yet the present Congress have as complete aUth?rity to 
REQUIRE of the States indefinite supplies of money for the common defense and general welfare, as the future 
Congress will have to reluire them of individual citizens; and the latter will be no more botind than the States 
themselves have bee-n, to pay the Quotas respectively taxed on them. had the States complied punctually with
the articles of Confederation, or could their compliance have been enforced by as peaceable means as may be 
used with success towards single persons, our past experience is very far from countenancing an opinion, that 
the State governments would have lost their constitutional powers, and have gradually undergone an entire 
consolidation. To maintain that such an event would have ensued, would be to say at once, that the existence 
of the State governments is incompatible with any system whatever that accomplishes the essental purposes
of the Union. PUBLIUS. FEDERALIST No. 46 The Influence of the State and Federal Governments Compared From the 
New York Packet. Tuesday, January 29, 1788. MADISON To the People of the State of New York: RESUMING the sub ject 
of the last paper, I proceed to inquire whether the federal government or the State governments will have the 
advantage with regard to the predilection and support of the people. Notwithstanding the different modes
in which they are appointed, we must consider both of them as substantially dependent on the great body of the 
citizens of the United States. I assume this position here as it respects the first, reserving the proofs for

