the mind; but a lesser degree of cold may, as well as a lesser degree of heat. <Phil>. Those bodies, therefore, 
Upon whose application to our ow-n, we perceive a moderate degree of heat, must be concluded to have a moderate
degree of heat or warmth in them; and those, upon whose application we feel a like degree of cold, must be thought
to have cold in them. <Hyl>. They must. <Phil>. Can any doctrine be true that -necessarily leads a man into an absurdity? 
<Hyl>. WithoUt doubt it can-not. <Phil>. Is it not an absurdity to think that the same thing should be at the same
time both cold and warm? <Hyl>. It is. <Phil>. Suppose now one of your hands hot, and the other cold, and that they 
are both at once put into the same vessel of {179} water, in an intermediate state; will not the water seem cold
to one hand, and warm to the other? <Hyl>. It will. <Phil>. Ought we not therefore, by your principles, to conclu_cle 
it is really both cold and warm at the same time, that is, according to your own concession, to believe an absurdity? 
<Hyl>. I confess it seems so. <Phil>. Consequently, the principles themselves are false, since you have granted 
that 710 true principle leads to an absurdity. <Hyl>. But, after all, can anything be more absurd than to say,
<there is no heat in the fire>? <Phil>. To make the point still clearer; tell me whether, in two cases exactly
alike, we ought not to make the same judgment? .<Hyl>. We ought. <Phil>. When a pin pricks your finger, cloth it 
not rend and divide the fibres of your flesh? <Hyl>. It cloth. <Phil>. And when a coal burns your finger, cloth it 
any more? <Hyl>. It doth -not <Phil>. Since, therefore, you -neither judge the sensation itself occasioned
by the pin, -nor anything like it to be in the pi-n; you should not, conformably to what you have now granted, judge 
the sensation occasioned by the fire, or anything like it, to be in the fire. <Hyl>. Well, since it must be so,
I am content to yield this point, and acknowledge that heat and cold are only sensations existing in our minds. 
eat there still remain qualities enough to secure the reality of external things. <Phil>. BUt what will you
say, Hylas, if it shall appear that the case is the same with regard to all other sensible qualities, and that
they can no more be supposed to exist without the mind, than heat and cold? <Hyl>. Then indeed you will have done 
something to the purpose; but that is what I despair of seeing proved. <Phil>. Let us examine them in order. What 
think you of <tastes>, do they exist without the mind, or -no? <Hyl>. Can any man in his senses doubt whether sugar 
is sweet, or wormwood bitter? <Phil>. Inform me, Hylas. Is a sweet taste a particular kind of pleasure or pleasant 
sensation, or is it -not? {18O} <Hyl>. It is. <Phil>. And is not bitterness some kind of Uneasiness or pain? <Hyl>.
I grant it. <Phil>. If therefore sugar and wormwood are Unthinking corporeal substances existing without
the mind, how can sweetness and bitterness, that is, Pleasure and pain, agree to them? <Hyl>. Hold, PhilonoUs,
I now see what it was delude time. You asked whether heat and cold, sweetness at were not particular sorts of pleasure 
and pain; to which simply, that they were. Whereas I should have thus distinguished: those qualities, as perceived
by us, are pleasures or pair existing in the external ob jects. We must not therefore conclude absolutely, that

