other cattle, the price -necessarily rises, and becomes proportionably higher or lower than that of other butcher's 
meat, according as the -nature of the coU2try, and the state of its agriculture, happen to render the feeding 
of hogs more or less expensive than that of other cattle. In France, according to Mr. Buffo-n, the price of pork 
is nearly equal to that of beef. In most parts of Great Britain it is at present somewhat higher. The great rise
in the price of both hogs and poultry has in Great Britain been frequently imputed to the diminution of the number 
of cottagers and other small occupiers of land; an event which has in every part of Europe been the immediate 
forerunner of improvement and better cultivation, but which at the same time may have contrinOtect to raise
the price of those articles both somewhat sooner and somewhat faster than it would otherwise have risen. As 
the poorest family can often maintain a cat or a dog without any expense, so the poorest occupiers of land can 
commonly maintain a few poultry, or a sow and a few pigs, at very little. The little offals of their own table, 
their whey, skimmed milk, and buttermilk, supply those animals with a part of their food, and they find the rest 
in the neighbouring fields without doing any sensible damage to anybody. By diminishing the -number of those 
small occupiers, therefore, the quantity of this sort of provisions, which is thus produced at little or no 
expense, must certainly have been a good deal diminished, and their price must conseeplently have been raised
both sooner and faster than it would otherwise have risen. Sooner or later, however, in the progress of improvement, 
it must at any rate have risen to the utmost height to which it is capable of rising; or to the price which pays the 
labour and expense of cultivating the land which furnishes them with food as well as these are paid upon the greater 
part of other cultivated land. The bUsiness of the dairy, like the feeding of hogs and poultry, is originally
carried on as a save-all. The cattle -necessarily kept upon the farm produce more milk than either the rearing
of their own young or the consumption of the farmer's family requires; and they produce most at one particular 
season. But of all the productions of land, milk is perhaps the most perishable. In the warm season, when it is 
most abOnclant, it will scarce keep four-and-twenty hours. The farmer, by making it into fresh butter, stores
a small part of it for a week: by making it into salt butter, for a year: and by making it into cheese, he stores a 
much greater part of it for several years. Part of all these is reser?ed for the use of his own family. The rest 
goes to market, in order to find the best price which is to be had, and which can scarce be so low as to discour?ge 
him from sending thither whatever is over and above the use of his own family. If it is very low, indeed, he will 
be likely to manage his dairy in a very slovenly and dirty manner, and will scarce perhaps think it worth while
to have a particular room or binding on purpose for it, but will suffer the nOsiness to be carried on amidst the 
smoke, filth, and nastiness of his own kitchen; as was the case of almost all the farmers' dairies in Scotland 
thirty or forty years ago, and as is the case of many of them still. The same causes which gradually raise the price

