more firmly in the baritone range. He put on a weapon belt and drew its green glowing sword. "well, Prometheus," 
he said to the sword, "At least I got laid. Even if that wasn't my own sperm I in jetted into her womb." # Ringman 
only heard about his son Gross Sword through the grapevine. After living with his lady love for eighteen months, 
here he was right back in his old cottage in town. Of course his cottage was actually a small castle, but without
Sick Sword in it it was hardly a keep. He'd -never managed to get back to the way things were before Peter Perfect 
and the Disgusting Characters had come along. He would've started drinking were he not concerned about keeping 
his paladinhood. So he had a third kid and he'd probably -never see him. He'd come back to Sick Sword's keep once,
all right -- for the sake of seeing his daughters if not her -- but she only tossed him out with an even louder "GET 
OUT" than before. The glimpse he'd gotten of her face before she slammed the door looked more like Omnio-n than 
it did like her. The -next thing he knew, Sick Sword had moved her keep several leagues away, back to where she'd 
first drawn it from the deck. He hadn't seen or heard from her since. well, a paladin operated best as a solo player
anyway; at least, that was how he tried to reassure himself. He picked a volume up from one of his shelves and flipped 
to the page he'd had marked. His doomed relationship hadn't been a total loss; she had taught him how to read.
# Disgusting Sword reached her first level of Druiclicism at age 10 1/2. Again, she was a slow developer, but she 
could still make it. Sick Sword took her to the edge of a centaurs' lair and pointed inside. "That's a centaur's 
lair," she told her daughter. "1 know," Disgusting Sword replied. "Good. And you know what to do?" "Of course." 
Disgusting Sword activated her permanent potion of flying at 150% effectiveness and wafted into the shallow 
cave. One psionic blast and several clatterings of gems later, she emerged as a 15th level druid, a 17th level 
monk, an 18th level thief, a 21st level paladin, a 31st level illU.sionist, a 38th level cleric, a 49th level magic-user, 
and a 58th level weapons mistress. "well," she said to Sick Sword, making sure all 93 of her hit points were in
place, "That was easy. How long before my magic sword becomes an artifact?" Ridiculous Sword was a little smarter. 
The only reasons Disgusting Sword had taken those particular levels of development was so that each of her classes 
would be of higher level than the one before it. Reading between the lines on the rules, Ridiculous Sword figured 
that it didn't matter what order her levels were stacked in, so long as the last class she chose had the highest 
experience level. As the bard class couldn't be started with a lawful-good alignment, she would -need that rules 
assumption if she were to become both a 20th level paladin and a 23rd level bard without losing her paladinhood. 
And so, hitting the centaur pits on her tenth birthday (only one day after her sister did), Ridiculous Sword 
emerged as a 23rd level druid, a 15th level assassin, a 17th level monk, a 17th level ranger, a 17th level thief,
a 23rd level bard, a 20th level paladin, a 31st level illusionist, a 38th level cleric, a 49th level magic-user,
and a 60th level weapons mistress. She would have gone farther in that last class had not the ... DUngeo-n Master

