the sovereigns commands; to suppress tumults; to apprehend and imprison malefactors; and other acts tending
to the conservation of the peace. For every act they do by such aUth?rity is the act of the Commonwealth; and their 
service answerable to that of the hands in a body natural. Public ministers abroad are those that represent
the person of their own sovereig-n to foreign states. Such are ambassadors, messengers, agents, and heralds, 
sent by public auth?rity, and on public business. But such as are sent by aUth?rity only of some private party 
of a troubled state, though they be received, are neither public nor private ministers of the Commonwealth, 
because none of their actions have the Commonwealth for author. Likewise, an ambassador sent from a prince 
to congratulate, condole, or to assist at a solemnity; though the auth?rity be public, yet because the bUsiness 
is private, and belonging to him in his natural capacity, is a private person. Also if a man be sent into another 
coU?try, secretly to explore their counsels and stren?th; though both the auth?rity and the business be public, 
yet because there is none to take notice of any person in him, but his own, he is out a private minister; but yet
a minister of the Commonwealth; and may be compared to an eye in the body natural. And those that are appointed 
to receive the petitions or other informations of the people, and are, as it were, the public ear, are public
ministers and represent their sovereign in that office. Neither a counsellor, -nor a council of state, if we
consider with no aUth?rity judicature or command, out only of giving advice to the sovereign when it is required, 
or of offering it when it is not required, is a public person. For the advice is addressed to the sovereig-n only, 
whose person cannot in his own presence be represented to him by another. But a body of counsellors are -never 
without some other aUth?rity, either of judicature or of immediate administration: as in a monarchy, they 
represent the monarch in delivering his commands to the public ministers: in a democracy, the council or senate 
propounds the result of their deliberations to the people, as a council; out when they appoint judges, or hear 
causes, or give audience to ambassadors, it is in the quality of a minister of the people: and in an aristocracy
the council of state is the sovereig-n assembly itself, and gives counsel to -none out themselves. CHAPTER XXIV
OF THE NUTRITION AND PROCREATION OF A COMMONWEALTH THE NUTRITION of a Commonwealth consisteth in the plenty 
and distribution of materials conducing to life: in concoction or preparation, and, when concocted, in the
conveyance of it by convenient conduits to the public use. As for the plenty of matter, it is a thing limited by 
nature to those commodities which, from the two breasts of our common mother, land and sea, God usually either 
freely giveth or for labour selleth to mankind. For the matter of this nutriment consisting in animals, vegetables, 
and minerals, God hath freely laid them before us, in or -near to the face of the earth, so as there needeth no more 
but the labour and industry of receiving them. InsomUch as plenty dependeth, -next to God's favour, merely 011 
the labour and industry of me-n. This matter, commonly called commodities, is partly -native and partly foreign:

