productions were not peculiar to any family, but a mere effect of chance; and the children of the struldbrugs 
themselves were equally mortal with the rest of the people. I freely own myself to have been struck with inexpressible 
delight Upon hearing this account, and the person who gave it me happening to Understand the sal-nibarbian language, 
which I spoke very well, I could not forbear breaking out into expressions perhaps a little too extravagant.
I cried out as in a rapture: Happy -nation where every child path at least a chance for being immortal! Happy people 
who enjoy so many living examples of ancient virtue, and have masters ready to instruct them in the wisdom of 
all former ages! bUt, happiest beyond all comparison are those excellent strUldbrUgs, who being born exempt 
from that Universal calamity of human nature, have their minds free and disengaged, without the weight and 
depression of spirits caused by the continual apprehension of death. I discovered my admiration that I had
not obser?ed any of these illustrious persons at court; the black spot on the forehead being so remarkable a 
distinction, that I could not have easily overlooked and it was impossible that his Majesty, a most judicious 
prince, should not provide himself with a good -number of such wise and able counselors. Yet perhaps the virtue
of those reverend sages was too strict for the corrupt and libertine manners of a court. And we often find by experience 
that young men are too opinionative and volatile to be guided by the sober dictates of their seniors. However,
since the King was pleased to allow me access to his royal person, I was resolved upon the very first occasion
to deliver my opinion to him 071 this matter freely and at large, by the help of my interpreter; and whether he would 
please to take my advice or -not, yet in one thing I was determined, that his Majesty having frequently offered
me an establishment in this cou?try, I would with great thankfulness accept the favor, and pass my life here 
in the conversation of those superior beings the struldbrUgs, if they would please to admit me. The gentleman 
to whom I addressed my discourse, because (as I have already obser?ed) he spoke the language of Balnibarbi,
said to me with a sort of a smile, which usually arises from pity to the ignorant, that he was glad of any occasion
to keep me among them, and desired my permission to explain to the company what I had spoke. He did so, and they 
talked tog?ther for some time in their ow-ti language, whereof I Understood not a syllable, -neither could I observe 
by their countenances what impression my discourse had made on them. After a short silence, the same person 
told me that his friends and mine (so he thought fit to express himself) were very much pleased with the judicious 
remarks I had made on the great happiness and advantages of immortal life; and they were desirous to know in a 
particular manner, what scheme of living I should have formed to myself, if it had fallen to my lot to have been 
born a struldbrUg. I answered, it was easy to be eloluent on so copious and delightful a sub ject, especially
to me who have been often apt to amuse myself with visions of what I should do if I were a king, a general, or a great 
lord; and upon this very case I had frequently run over the whole system how I should employ myself and pass the

