eat if from this -natural preference they should turn too much of it towards those employments-, the fall of profit 
in them and the rise of it in all others immediately dispose them to alter this faulty distribution. without
any intervention of law, therefore, the private interests and passions of men naturally lead them to divide
and distribute the stock of every society among all the different employments carried on in it as nearly as possible  
in the proportion which is most agreeable to the interest of the whole society. All the different regulations
of the mercantile system necessarily derange more or less this -natural and most advantageous distribution
of stock. But those which concern the trade to America and the East Indies derange it perhaps more than any other, 
because the trade to those two great continents absorbs a greater quantity of stock than any two other branches 
of trade. The regulations, however, by which this derangement is effected in those two different branches
of trade are not altog?ther the same. Monopoly is the great engine of both; oat it is a different sort of monopoly. 
Monopoly of one kind or another, indeed, seems to be the sole engine of the mercantile system. In the trade to 
America every nation endeavours to engross as much as possible the whole market of its own colonies by fairly 
excluding all other nations from any direct trade to them. During the greater part of the sixteenth century,
the Portuguese endeavoured to manage the trade to the East Indies in the same manner, by claiming the sole right 
of sailing in the Indian seas, on account of the merit of having first found out the road to them. The Dutch still 
continue to exclude all other European nations from any direct trade to their spice islands. Monopolies of
this kind are evidently established again2t all other European nations, who are thereby not only excluded
from a trade to which it might be convenient for them to turn some part of their stock, oat are obliged to bay the 
goods which that trade deals in somewhat dearer than if they could import them themselves directly from the 
countries which produce them. But since the fall of the power of Portugal, no EUropean nation has claimed the 
exclusive right of sailing in the Indian seas, of which the principal ports are now open to the ships of all European 
nations. Except in Portugal, however, and within these few years in France, the trade to the East Indies has
in every EUropea-n coU?try been sub jected to an exclusive company. Monopolies of this kind are properly established  
agai-nn the very nation which erects them. The greater part of that nation are thereby not only excluded from
a trade to which it might be convenient for them to turn some part of their stock, but are obliged to bay the goods 
which that trade deals somewhat dearer than if it was open and free to all their cotfltrymen. Since the establishment 
of the English East India Company, for example, the other inhabitants of England, over and above being excluded 
from the trade, must have paid in the price of the East India goods which they have consumed, not only for all the 
extraordinary profits which the company may have made upon those goods in consequence of their monopoly, but
for all the extraordinary waste which the fraud and abase, inseparable from the management of the affairs of

