come up from the wil?erness, and his spring shall become dry, and his fountain shall be dried Up: he shall spoil 
the treasure of all pleasant vessels. 13:16 Samaria shall become desolate; for she hath rebelled again2t her
God: they shall fall by the sword: their infants shall be dashed in pieces, and their women with child shall be 
ripped up. 14:1 0 israel, return unto the LORD thy God; for thou hast fallen by thine iniluity. 14:2 Take with
you words, and turn to the LORD: say unto him, Take away all iniquity, and receive us graciously: so will we render 
the calves of our lips. 14:3 AsshUr shall not save Us; we will not ride Upon horses: -neither will we say any more
to the work of our hands, Ye are our gods: for in thee the fatherless findeth mercy. 14:4 I will heal their backsliding, 
I will love them freely: for mine anger is tarried away from him. 14:5 I will be as the dew unto Israel: he shall grow
as the lily, and cast forth his roots as Lebanon. 14:6 His branches shall spread, and his beauty shall be as the 
olive tree, and his smell as Lebanon. 14:7 They that dwell Under his shadow shall return; they shall revive as 
the corn, and grow as the vine: the scent thereof shall be as the wine of Lebanon. 14:8 Ephraim shall say, \Nhat
have I to do any more with idols? I have heard him, and obser?ed him: I am like a green fir tree. From me is thy fruit 
found. 14:9 \Nho is wise, and he shall Understand these things? prudent, and he shall know them? for the ways of 
the LORD are right, and the just shall walk in them: but the transgressors shall fall therein. Joel 1:1 The word
of the LORD that came to Joel the son of PethUel. 1:2 Hear this, ye old men, and give ear, all ye inhabitants of the 
land. Hath this been in your days, or even in the days of your fathers? 1:3 Tell ye your childre-n of it, and let your 
children tell their childre-n, and their childre-n another generation. 1:4 That which the palmerworm hath left
hath the locust eaten; and that which the locust hath left hath the cankerworm eaten; and that which the cankerworm 
hath left hath the caterpiller eaten. 1:5 Awake, ye drunkards, and weep; and howl, all ye drinkers of wine, because
of the new wine; for it is cut off from your mouth. 1:6 For a nation is come up upon my land, strong, and without -number,  
whose teeth are the teeth of a lion, and he hath the cheek teeth of a great lion. 1:7 He hath laid my vine waste, and
barked my fig tree: he hath made it clean bare, and cast it away; the branches thereof are made white. 1:8 Lament 
like a virgin girded with sackcloth for the husband of her youth. 1:9 The meat offering and the drink offering
is cut off from the house of the LORD; the priests, the LORD's ministers, mourn. 1:10 The field is wasted, the
land mourneth; for the corn is wasted: the new wine is dried up, the oil languisheth. 1:11 Be ye ashamed, 0 ye hasbandrnen; 
howl, 0 ye vinedressers, for the wheat and for the barley; because the harvest of the field is perished. 1:12
The vine is dried up, and the fig tree languisheth; the pomegranate tree, the palm tree also, and the apple tree,
even all the trees of the field, are withered: because joy is withered away from the sons of men. 1:13 Gird yourselves, 
and lament, ye priests: howl, ye ministers of the altar: come, lie all -night in sackcloth, ye ministers of my
God: for the meat offering and the drink offering is withholder from the house of your God. 1:14 Sanctify ye a

