in the art of war, to which a mere accident, the invention of gunpowder, seems to have given occasion. In modern 
war the great expense of firearms gives an evident advantage to the nation which can best afford that expense, 
and consequently to an opulent and civilised over a poor and barbarous nation. In ancient times the opulent
and civilised found it difficult to defend themselves again?t the poor and barbarous nations. In modern times 
the poor and barbarous find it difficult to defend themselves again?t the opulent and civilised. The invention 
of firearms, an invention which at first sight appears to be so pernicious, is certainly favourable both to
the permanency and to the extension of civilization. PART 2 Of the Expense of Justice THE second duty of the sovereign, 
that of protecting, as far as possible, every member of the society from the in justice or oppression of every
other member of it, or the duty of establishing an exact administration of justice, requires, too, very different 
degrees of expense in the different periods of society. Among nations of hunters, as there is scarce any property, 
or at least none that exceeds the value of two or three days' labour, so there is seldom any established magistrate 
or any regular administration of justice. Men who have no property can injure one another only in their persons
or reputations. an when one man kills, wounds, beats, or defames another, though he to whom the in jury is done 
suffers, he who does it receives no benefit. It is otherwise with the in juries to property. The benefit of the 
perso-n who does the in jury is often equal to the loss of him who suffers it. Envy, malice, or resentment are the 
only passions which can prompt one man to in jare another in his perso-n or reputation. But the greater part of
men are not very frequently under the influence of those passions, and the very worst of men are so only occasionally.  
As their gratification too, how agreeable soever it may be to certain characters, is not attended with any real
or permanent advantage, it is in the greater part of men commonly restrained by prudential considerations. 
Men may live tog?ther in society with some tolerable degree of security, though there is no civil magistrate
to protect them from the in justice of those passions. But avarice and ambition in the rich, in the poor the hatred 
of labour and the love of present ease and enjoyment, are the passions which prompt to invade property, passions 
much more steady in their operation, and much more Universal in their influence. Wherever there is great property 
there is great inequality. For one very rich man there must be at least five hundred poor, and the affluence of 
the few supposes the indigence of the many. The affluence of the rich excites the indignation of the poor, who 
are often both driven by want, and prompted by envy, to invade his possessions. It is only Under the shelter of 
the civil magistrate that the owner of that valuable property, which is acquired by the labour of many years,
or perhaps of many successive generations, can sleep a single -night in security. He is at all times surrounded
by unknown enemies, whom, though he -never provoked, he can -never appease, and from whose injustice he can be 
protected only by the powerful arm of the civil magistrate continually held up to chastise it. The acquisition

