seal the slight gap left between the bridge and the ship. A cap of composite material was then fit over the bridge 
to blend it smoothly with the rest of the saucer section. "Lets go take a look at our bridge." Captain Anthony 
said stepping off the girder and accelerating toward the Vigilante. to be continued T H E V I G I L
ANTE II "The Shakedown" .... Have ever you stood where the silences brood, And vast the Horizons begin, At the 
dawn of the clay to behold far away The goal you would strive for and win? Yet ah! in the night when you gain to the 
height, With the vast pool of heaven star-spawned, Afar and agleam, like a valley of dream, Still mocks you a
land of Beyond.  Robert w. Service "THE LAND OF BEYOND" Commander Tarva and Captain Anthony stood in front 
of the turbo lift door waiting to enter the bridge. Commander Tarva spoke into her communicator with Construction 
while waiting for the bridge to be pressurized. \then life support was established the turbo lift door opened.
Captain Anthony and Commander Tarva were alone when they stepped onto the bridge. Only the emergency lights 
shining down from hidden recesses illu_nninatecl the bridge. The major color scheme was gray with black accents. 
There seemed to be more chairs then expected, all tightly wrapped in plastic. Before they could make it half
way around the bridge turbo lift two opened allowing the construction crew in. They immediately crawled Under 
the control banks and opened other panels. Slowly, computer screens began to light up and the main lights came 
on showing the whole bridge. Tarva and Captain Anthony without saying a word to each other began tearing the 
plastic off the chairs. Each station had a chair and was well designed for total access. The current trend in
star ship bridges was to have several stations as standing positions, no chairs available. In the Vigilante 
this could cause a problem if they ever actually tried to use the controlled worm hole effect. The chairs had
high backs with emergency restraints and belts. The bridge had the standard layout with Captai-n in the middle 
of the Bridge. Pilot and Navigator in front of and to either side of the Captai-n. Next to the Captain on the left 
was the Security station. On the other side of the Captai-n was the First Officer station. The five stations in 
the middle of the bridge each had a wrap around counsel. The Captain's chair also had special controls on the 
restrain arms. The Captain and First Officer's consoles were designed mainly for ship wide communications 
they could also be quickly reconfigured for all other bridge functions. Tarva tried her chair out for size.
The cloth seat seemed to form to fit. The worker laying Under her console stood up and pushed a bUtto-n on it. The 
console lit up and Tarva recognized it as a standard console with emphasis on communications. She pushed a button 
and said "Attention, all bridge crew please report to the bridge." As the last of the Bridge shifts showed up,
the last of the workers was leaving. More than fifteen people stood on the front of the bridge in front of the main 
view scree-n. Many appeared to have been gotten out of bed, they were yawning and didn't have perfectly groomed 
hair. Captain Anthony sat in his chair and waited while First Officer Tarva did a roll call of the crew before

