even forty feet high, as was the salt pillar which happened to be standing at the visit of Corrirrienier Lynch in 1848; 
but this only added a new proof to the miracle, for the text was remembered, "There were giants in those days."
Out of the mass of works of pilgrims during the fifteenth century I select just one more as typical of the theological 
view then dominant, and this is the -noted book of Felix Fabri, a preaching friar of Ulm. I select him, because
even so eminent an au_th?rity in our own time as Dr. Edward Robinson declares him to have been the most thorough, 
thoughtful, and enlightened traveller of that century. Fabri is greatly impressed by the wonders of the Dead
Sea, and typical of his honesty influenced by faith is his account of the Dead Sea fruit; he describes it with 
almost perfect accuracy, but adds the statement that when mature it is "filled with ashes and cinders." As to
the salt statue, he says: "We saw the place between the sea and MoUnt Segor, but could not see the statue itself 
because we were too far distant to see anything of human size; but we saw it with firm faith, because we believed 
Scripture, which speaks of it; and we were filled with wonder." To sustain absolute faith in the statue he reminds 
his reader's that "God is able even of these stones to raise up seed to Abraham," and goes into a long argument, 
discussing such transformations as those of King Atlas and Pygmalion's statue, with a multitude of others, 
winding up with the case, given in the miracles of St. Jerome, of a heretic who was changed into a log of wood, which 
was then burned. He gives a statement of the Hebrews that Lot's wife received her peculiar punishment because
she had refused to add salt to the food of the angels when they visited her, and he preaches a short sermon in which
he says that, as salt is the condiment of food, so the salt statue of Lot's wife "gives us a condiment of wisdom."[[233]] 
There were, indeed, many discrepancies in the testimony of travellers regarding the salt pillar--so many,
in fact, that at a later period the learned Dom Calmet acknowledged that they shook his belief in the whole matter; 
but, during this earlier time, under the complete sway of the theological spirit, these difficulties only
gave new and more glori?U_s opportunities for faith. For, if a considerable interval occurred between the washing 
of one salt pillar out of existence and the washing of another into existence, the idea arose that the statue, 
by virtue of the soul which still remained in it, had departed on some mysterious excursion. Did it happe-n that
one statue was washed out one year in one place and another statue another year in another place, this difficulty 
was surmounted by believing that Lot's wife still walked about. Did it happe-n that a salt column was undermined 
by the rains and fell, this was believed to be but another sign of life. Did a pillar happen to be covered in part
by the sea, this was enough to arouse the belief that the statue from time to time descended into the Dead Sea depths--possibly 
to satisfy that old fatal curiosity regarding her former neighbours. Did some smaller block of salt happen
to be washed out near the statue, it was believed that a household dog, also transformed into salt, had followed 
her back from beneath the deep. Did more statues than one appear at one time, that simply made the mystery more

