Jimmy's skin came out toughened and weathered (although it was still 18 charisma skin). Muscles bulged from 
his body where he didn't know half-elves could have muscles. The great phantom character sheet in the sky 
told him that he had the full 14 hit points. He felt like vomiting. Ridiculous Sword approached him and put her 
arm around his shoulders. She looked into his eyes, and said, "Welcome to level one." # Peter Perfect stopped 
scanning with his eyes of the eagle from his warhorse's saddle. Across about a mile of dry lakebed, he'd seen 
what he was hoping for. "Well well well," he told his horse and his holy sword, "It looks like Ringrnan's decided
to face me on my own turf. We'll see how well he handles himself without a magic ballista!" He put his fa-nifty glasses 
away, held Prometheus in his right hand and the warhorse's reins in his left, and with a tiny jolt instructed
the horse to trot toward the approaching Ringman. He surveyed the landscape one more time: absolutely flat,
not a tree or a bush or a rock or a dumb old human to mar the expanse of barrenness. This place had his -name written 
all over it; nothing was quite so impressive as his castle jutting up from the center of all this nothingness.
It also gave Ringman and any goody-two-shoes cohorts he might happen to be carrying along with him -nowhere to 
hide. Like that brownie Peter saw riding on his shoulder. Yeah, he figured as he rode closer, maybe he'd capture
the brownie and torture it just to see what Ringman would do. Or maybe he'd torture Ringman to see what the brownie 
would do. Or perhaps he'd torture Ringman and the brownie to see what Ringrnan's horse would do- Ringman rode
up toward him on his own horse, unusually confident for being about to face his old nemesis. Homer the brownie 
rode on his left shoulder, meteorite-iron steel plate barding rode almost weightlessly over the warhorse's
body, and Ringman's holy avenger rode in its scabbard rather than in his hand. He flinched as Peter Perfect shot 
him a sinister grin, but quickly recuperated. He also -noticed that Peter Perfect had probably been reading
the Other Book of Infinite Wisdom; he'd traded in the gauntlets and chausses of his +S aclarnantite-alloyed plate 
mail for +6 pure-aclamantite-metal full plate armor. Their horses trotted toward each other Until they were 
practically -nose to nose. "Well, Ringman, old buddy, old pal," Peter Perfect chided, "What brings you to my
realm of dread?" 'How can the DU_ngeon Master let this guy stay a paladin?!' Ringman thought. "I've come here 
to settle a grudge that's more than a decade old," he told him. "Oh?" Peter Perfect asked sarcastically. "And
what grudge might that be, hmm?" Ringman shook his head and grinned a bit. "YoU and me, you disgrace to palaclinhood, 
you and I. So long as you stay the way you are right now, I'm ashamed to share your character class." "Oh, I see.
So you've finally come to die." Peter cracked his knuckles. "No," Ringman replied quite calmly, "I've come
to bring you down." The beardless paladin chuckled through his -nose. "You must be joking. You? Alone?!" "Ah, 
but I'm not alone," Ringman obser?ed. "I've brought a friend." "Pphhh, what, the late Sick Sword's little 
brownie?" "Homer, sure, I brought him." A flurry of scintillating dust grains wafted away from a spot two feet

