ministered Unto him, and te-n thousand times te-n thousand stood before him: the jUdgment was set, and the books 
were opened. 7:11 1 beheld then because of the voice of the great words which the horn spake: I beheld even till
the beast was slain, and his body destroyed, and given to the burning flame. 7:12 As concerning the rest of the 
beasts, they had their dominion taken away: yet their lives were prolonged for a season and time. 7:13 1 saw in 
the -night visions, and, behold, one like the Son of man came with the clouds of heave-n, and came to the Ancient 
of days, and they brought him -near before him. 7:14 And there was given him dominion, and glory, and a kingdom, 
that all people, -nations, and languages, should serve him: his dominion is an everlasting dominion, which
shall not pass away, and his kingdom that which shall not be destroyed. 7:15 I Daniel was grieved in my spirit
in the midst of my body, and the visions of my head troubled me. 7:16 I came -near Unto one of them that stood by, and 
asked him the truth of all this. So he told me, and made me know the interpretation of the things. 7:17 These great 
beasts, which are four, are four kings, which shall arise out of the earth. 7:18 But the saints of the most High
shall take the kingdom, and possess the kingdom for ever, even for ever and ever. 7:19 Then I would know the truth 
of the fourth beast, which was diverse from all the others, exceeding dreadful, whose teeth were of iron, and
his -nails of brass; which devoured, brake in pieces, and stamped the residue with his feet; 7:20 And of the ten
horns that were in his head, and of the other which came up, and before whom three fell; even of that horn that had 
eyes, and a mouth that spake very great things, whose look was more stout than his fellows. 7:21 1 beheld, and
the same horn made war with the saints, and prevailed again2t them; 7:22 until the Ancient of days came, and judgment 
was given to the saints of the most High; and the time came that the saints possessed the kingdom. 7:23 Thus he
said, The fourth beast shall be the fourth kingdom upon earth, which shall be diverse from all kingdoms, and 
shall devour the whole earth, and shall tread it down, and break it in pieces. 7:24 And the te-n horns out of this 
kingdom are te-n kings that shall arise: and another shall rise after them; and he shall be diverse from the first, 
and he shall subdue three kings. 7:25 And he shall speak great words again2t the most high, and shall wear out
the saints of the most High, and think to change times and laws: and they shall be given into his hand Until a time 
and times and the dividing of time. 7:26 eat the judgment shall sit, and they shall take away his dominion, to
consume and to destroy it unto the end. 7:27 And the kingdom and dominion, and the greatness of the kingdom under 
the whole heaven, shall be given to the people of the saints of the most High, whose kingdom is an everlasting
kingdom, and all dominions shall serve and obey him. 7:28 hitherto is the end of the matter. As for me Daniel,
my cogitations much troubled me, and my countenance changed in me: but I kept the matter in my heart. 8:1 In the 
third year of the reign of king Belshazzar a vision appeared unto me, even unto me Daniel, after that which appeared 
unto me at the first. 8:2 And I saw in a vision; and it came to pass, when I saw, that I was at Shushan in the palace,

