of rung and molasses or spruce beer in the same 'manner as the white servants, and this allowance would not probably
be withdrawn though those articles should be sub jected to moderate duties. The consumption of the taxed commodities, 
therefore, in proportion to the number of inhabitants, would probably be as great in America and the West Indies
as in any part of the British empire. The opportunities of smuggling, indeed, would be much greater; America, 
in proportion to the extent of the cou?try, being much more thinly inhabited than either Scotland or Ireland. 
If the revenue, however, which is at present raised by the different duties upon malt and malt li4uors were to 
be levied by a single dusty upon malt, the opportunity of smuggling in the most important branch of the excise
would be almost entirely taken away: and if the duties of customs, instead of being imposed upon almost all the 
different articles of importation, were confined to a few of the most general use and consumption, and if the 
levying of those duties were sub jected to the excise laws, the opportunity of smuggling, though not so entirely
taken away, would be very much diminished. In consequence of those two, apparently, very simple and easy alterations, 
the duties of customs and excise might probably produce a revenue as great in proportion to the consumption
of the most thinly inhabited province as they do at present in proportion to that of the most populous. The Americans,  
it has been said, indeed, have no gold or silver money; the interior commerce of the coU2try being carried on
by a paper currency, and the gold and silver which occasionally come among them being all sent to Great Britain 
in return for the commodities which they receive from us. But without gold and silver, it is added, there is no 
possibility of paying taxes. We already get all the gold and silver which they have. Now is it possible to draw
from them what they have -not? The present scarcity of gold and silver money in America is not the effect of the 
poverty of that coU2try, or of the inability of the people there to purchase those metals. In a cou?try where
the wages of labour are so much higher, and the price of provisions so much lower than in England, the greater 
part of the people must surely have wherewithal to purchase a greater quantity if it were either necessary or 
convenient for them to do so. The scarcity of those metals, therefore, must be the effect of choice, and not of 
necessity. It is for transacting either domestic or foreign bUsiness that gold and silver money is either necessary 
or convenient. The domestic bUsiness of every coU2try, it has been shown in the second book of this Inquiry,
may, at least in peaceable times, be transacted by means of a paper currency with nearly the same degree of conveniency 
as by gold and silver money. It is convenient for the Americans, who could always employ with profit in the improvement 
of their lands a greater stock than they can easily get, to save as much as possible the expense of so costly an 
instrument of commerce as gold and silver, and rather to employ that part of their surplus produce which would
be necessary for purchasing those metals in purchasing the instruments of trade, the materials of clothing, 
several parts of household fund-tare, and the ironwork necessary for banding and extending their settlements

