methods wherein the Mind we depend on excites in us the ideas of sense, are called the laws of -nature; and these 
we learn by experience, which teaches us that such and such ideas are attended with such and such other ideas, 
in the ordinary course of things. 31. This gives us a sort of foresight which enables us to regulate our actions
for the benefit of life. And without this we should be eternally at a loss; we could not know how to act anything 
that might procure us the least pleasure, or remove the least pain of sense. That food nourishes, sleep refreshes, 
and fire warms us; that to sow in the seed-time is the way to reap in the harvest; and in general that to obtain such 
or such ends, such or such means are conducive- all this we know, not by discovering any necessary connexion 
between our ideas, but only by the observation of the settled laws of nature, without which we should be all in
Uncertainty and confusion, and a grown man no more know how to manage himself in the affairs of life than an infant 
just born. 32. And yet this consistent uniform working, which so evidently displays the goodness and wisdom
of that Governing Spirit whose Will constitutes the laws of -nature, is so far from leading our thoughts to Him, 
that it rather sends them wandering after second causes. For, when we perceive certain ideas of Sense constantly 
followed by other ideas and we know this is not of our own doing, we forthwith attribute power and agency to the 
ideas themselves, and make one the cause of another, than which nothing can be more absurd and unintelligible. 
Thus, for example, having obser?ed that when we perceive by sight a certain round itliniA0115 figure we at the same 
time perceive by touch the idea or sensation called heat, we do from thence conclUde the sun to be the cause of 
heat. And in like manner perceiving the motion and collision of bodies to be attended with sound, we are inclined 
to think the latter the effect of the former. 33. The ideas imprinted on the Senses by the Author of -nature are 
called real things; and those excited in the imagination being less regular, vivid, and constant, are more
properly termed ideas, or images of things, which they copy and represent. But then our sensations, be they 
-never so vivid and distinct, are -nevertheless ideas, that is, they exist in the mind, or are perceived by it,
as truly as the ideas of its own framing. The ideas of Sense are allowed to have more reality in them, that is, to 
be more strong, orderly, and coherent than the creatures of the mind; but this is no argument that they exist 
without the mind. They are also less dependent on the spirit, or thinking substance which perceives them, in 
that they are excited by the will of another and more powerful spirit; yet still they are ideas, and certainly
no idea, whether faint or strong, can exist otherwise than in a mind perceiving it. 34. Before we proceed any
farther it is necessary we spend some time in answering ob jections which may probably be made againfl the principles 
we have hitherto laid down. In doing of which, if I seem too prolix to those of wick apprehensions, I hope it may
be pardoned, since all men do not eckally apprehend things of this -nature, and I am willing to be understood by 
every one. First, then, it will be ob jected that by the foregoing principles all that is real and substantial

