level they were on, was more like a catwalk. It consisted of grating similar to what the elevator was made of. 
The catwalk slowly spiraled down to the bottom of the foundry. From their current position, though, the team
could not see the far side of the area. The Drop Team reassembled and started down the catwalk in their standard
two by two cover. So far, they hadn't seen any movement in the area but weren't going to take any chances. 
When Team Three tested the elevator, they found it still in perfect working order. Their fist stop was the level
they had visited previously. The first goal was to try accessing one of the ports. This time, however, they would 
only monitor the first data level. There was no apparent response after te-n minutes so they disconnected and 
headed to the machinery. In the machinery area, the Borg continued to ignore the team infiltrating directly
among them. The new ob jective was to study the shop and determine what was being made. Another goal was to determine 
the level of technology being employed. Were the Borg manufacturing at a level above what the Federation was
capable of, and if they were, could they learn from it. It was apparent that the Borg could see the team members. 
As the Borg wandered about performing their tasks, they would ad just their paths so as not to run into anyone. 
The group had split into four sub-teams to more effectively chart the area. They were soon lost in the machinery
that towered above them, making most feel like insects. It was soon discovered that there were walk ways connecting 
the taller machines. Giving all a new perspective on the area. One of the subteams climbed to the catwalks for
a better view of the area. The ladders were actually only long, flattened U's built into the sides of the machines. 
From the catwalks it was obvious that this manufacturing area stretched out for hundreds of meters beyond their 
entry point. Beyond, was what appeared to be another series of partitioned rooms, similar to what they had just 
left. "Lets make for the far side." Utlin said "Maybe there are more relics." The team gathered on the far side
after two hours of negotiating through the maze of machinery. None had been harassed or in anyway -noticed by 
the Borg working in the area. They fanned out and walked quickly across the fifty or so meters of open area before 
the partitions. The new area was different from the partitioned section on the far side of the level. The area
was not only w?Iled but covered. The w?Ils were sturdy and seemed thick. The tri-corders could not scan through 
the material and could not positively identify it. Where the partitions they had encountered originally were
open and easily accessible, they could not immediately find an opening or door. "What is it?" one of the Techs 
asked. "Perhaps it's a storage facility." another volUnteered. "Perhaps," Utlin said "We should find an entrance
and find out." He then pointed to half the team and sent them in one direction while he and the rest headed in the 
other. "Let us know if there are any changes in the tricorder readings." Anthony said as the teams separated.
The w?Ils were in panels of the same size as the dividers on the other side. These w?lls were dark green, almost 
black and covered with a thin layer of dust. After te-n minutes, the other team hailed Utlin. "Sir, we've found

