the vision is not of something that must enter but of something present before all ELSE, before the Intellect
itself made any movement. Yet it is the Intellect that must move, to come and to go- going because it has not known 
where it should stay and where that presence stays, the nowhere contained. And if the Intellect, too, could
hold itself in that -nowhere- not that it is ever in place; it too is Uncontainecf, Utterly Unplace,d- it would remain 
for ever in the vision of its prior, or, indeed, not in vision but in identity, all duality annulled. out it is 
Intellect [having a sphere of its own] and, when it is to see, it must see by that in it which is not Intellect [by
its divinest power]. No doubt it is wonderful that The First should thus be present without any coming, and that, 
while it is nowhere, nowhere is it -not; but wonderful though this be in itself, the contrary would be more wonderful 
to those who know. Of course -neither this contrary -nor the wonder at it can be entertained. eat we must explain:
9. Everything brought into being under some principle not itself is contained either within its maker or, if 
there is any intermediate, within that: having a prior essential to its being, it -needs that prior always, otherwise 
it would not be contained at all. It is the order of -nature: The last in the immediately preceding lasts, things 
of the order of the Firsts within their prior-firsts, and so thing within thing up to the very pinnacle of source.
That Source, having no prior, cannot be contained: uncontainect by any of those other forms of being, each held 
within the series of priors, it is orbed round all, but so as not to be pointed off to hold them part for part; it 
possesses but is not possessed. Holding all- though itself -nowhere held- it is omnipresent, for where its presence 
failed something would elude its hold. At the same time, in the sense that it is -nowhere held, it is not present: 
thus it is both present and not present; not present as not being circumscribed by anything; yet, as being utterly 
unattached, not inhibited from presence at any point. That inhibition would mean that the First was determined
by some other being; the later series, the-n, would be without part in the Supreme; God has His limit and is no longer 
self-governed but mastered by inferiors. While the contained must be where its container is, what is unco-ntainect 
by place is not debarred from any: for, imagine a place where it is not and evidently some other place retains
it; at once it is contained and there is an end of its placeless-ness. eat if the "-nowhere" is to stand and the ascription 
of a "where," implying station in the extern, is to fall, then nothing can be left void; and at once- nothing void,
yet no point containing- God is sovereignly present through all. we cannot think of something of God here and 
something else there, -nor of all God gathered at some one spot: there is an instantaneous presence everywhere, 
nothing containing and nothing left void, everything therefore fans held by the divine. Consider our Universe. 
There is -none before it and therefore it is -not, itself, in a universe or in any place- what place was there before 
the universe came to be?- its linked members form and occupy the whole. But Soul is not in the universe, on the
contrary the universe is in the Soul; bodily substance is not a place to the Soul; Soul is contained in Intellectual-Principl

