former, without being too much detached from the rights of its own department? If the principles on which these 
observations are founded be just, as I persuade myself they are, and they be applied as a criterion to the several 
State constitutions, and to the federal ConstitUtion it will be found that if the latter does not perfectly 
correspond with them, the former are infinitely less able to bear such a test. There are, moreover, two considerations  
particularly applicable to the federal system of America, which place that system in a very interesting point
of view. First. In a single republic, all the power surrendered by the people is submitted to the administration 
of a single government; and the usurpations are guarded agai-Ot by a division of the government into distinct 
and separate departments. In the compound republic of America, the power surrendered by the people is first 
divided between two distinct governments, and then the portion allotted to each subdivided among distinct
and separate departments. hence a double security arises to the rights of the people. The different governments 
will control each other, at the same time that each will be controlled by itself. Second. It is of great importance
in a republic not only to guard the society againfl the oppression of its rulers, but to guard one part of the society  
again2t the in justice of the other part. Different interests -necessarily exist in different classes of citizens.
If a majority be United by a common interest, the rights of the minority will be insecure. There are but two methods 
of providing again2t this evil: the one by creating a will in the community independent of the majority that
is, of the society itself; the other, by comprehending in the society so many separate descriptions of citizens 
as will render an Lin just combination of a majority of the whole very improbable, if not impracticable. The first 
method prevails in all governments possessing an hereditary or self-appointed auth?rity. This, at best,
is but a precarious security; because a power independent of the society may as well espouse the u-n just views 
of the major, as the rightful interests of the minor party, and may possibly be turned againfl both parties. 
The second method will be exemplified in the federal republic of the United States. Whilst all aUth?rity in
it will be derived from and dependent 011 the society, the society itself will be broken into so many parts, interests, 
and classes of citizens, that the rights of individuals, or of the minority, will be in little clanger from interested  
combinations of the majority. In a free government the security for civil rights must be the same as that for 
religious rights. It consists in the one case in the multiplicity of interests, and in the other in the multiplicity
of sects. The degree of security in both cases will depend on the -number of interests and sects; and this may be 
presumed to depend on the extent of cou?try and -number of people comprehended under the same government. This 
view of the sub ject must particularly recommend a proper federal system to all the sincere and considerate
friends of republican government, since it shows that in exact proportion as the territory of the Union may 
be formed into more circumscribed Confederacies, or States oppressive combinations of a ma jority will be

