of Orman the Jebusite. 21:16 And David lifted up his eyes, and saw the angel of the LORD stand between the earth 
and the heaven, having a drawn sword in his hand stretched out over Jerusalem. Then David and the elders of Israel, 
who were clothed in sackcloth, fell Upon their faces. 21:17 And David said Unto God, Is it not I that commanded
the people to be numbered? even I it is that have sinned and done evil indeed; but as for these sheep, what have
they done? let thine hand, I pray thee, 0 LORD my God, be on me, and on my father's house; but not on thy people, that 
they should be plagued. 21:18 Then the angel of the LORD commanded Gad to say to David, that David should go up,
and set up an altar Unto the LORD in the threshingfloor of Orna-n the Jebusite. 21:19 And David went up at the saying 
of Gad, which he spake in the -name of the LORD. 21:20 And Orman turned back, and saw the angel; and his four sons 
with him hid themselves. Now Ornan was threshing wheat. 21:21 And as David came to Orna-n, Orna-n looked and saw 
David, and went out of the threshingfloor, and bowed himself to David with his face to the ground. 21:22 Then 
David said to Orna-n, Grant me the place of this threshingfloor, that I may build an altar therein Unto the LORD:
thou shalt grant it me for the full price: that the plague may be stayed from the people. 21:23 And Orna-n said unto 
David, Take it to thee, and let my lord the king do that which is good in his eyes: lo, I give thee the oxen also for 
burnt offerings, and the threshing instruments for wood, and the wheat for the meat offering; I give it all.
21:24 And king David said to Ornan, Nay; but I will verily bay it for the full price: for I will not take that which
is thine for the LORD, nor offer burnt offerings without cost. 21:25 So David gave to Ornan for the place six hundred 
shekels of gold by weight. 21:26 And David built there an altar unto the LORD, and offered burnt offerings and
peace offerings, and called Upon the LORD; and he answered him from heaven by fire upon the altar of burnt offering. 
21:27 And the LORD commanded the angel; and he put up his sword again into the sheath thereof. 21:28 At that time 
when David saw that the LORD had answered him in the threshingfloor of Orna-n the Jebusite, then he sacrificed 
there. 21:29 For the tabernacle of the LORD, which Moses made in the wil?erness, and the altar of the burnt offering, 
were at that season in the high place at Gibeon. 21:30 But David could not go before it to enluire of God: for he
was afraid because of the sword of the angel of the LORD. 22:1 Then David said, This is the house of the LORD God, 
and this is the altar of the burnt offering for Israel. 22:2 And David commanded to gather tog?ther the strangers 
that were in the land of Israel; and he set masons to hew wrought stones to build the house of God. 22:3 And David 
prepared iron in abundance for the -nails for the doors of the gates, and for the joinings; and brass in abUnclance 
without weight; 22:4 Also cedar trees in abUndance: for the ZicIonians and they of Tare brought much cedar wood 
to David. 22:5 And David said, Solomon my son is young and tender, and the house that is to be blinded for the LORD 
must be exceeding magnifica:, of fame and of glory throughout all countries: I will therefore now make preparation 
for it. So David prepared abundantly before his death. 22:6 Then he called for Solomon his son, and charged him

